Guide to the Goldstaub family papers, 1951-2008
Goldstaub family papers, 1951-2008
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Goldstaub family papers, 1951-2008
7567
Goldstaub family
6.0 cubic feet
Papers, photographs, correspondence, posters, videotapes, audiotapes, 8mm film reels, CDs, musical score, press releases, ephemera, items of clothing, birth and death certificates, scrapbooks, autobiographical essay.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The Goldstaub family papers relate to the effect on the family of Sylvia and Bernie Goldstaub when their son Mark came out to them as a gay man in 1977 and later when he became HIV-positive. The collection includes an audiotape of "Venetian Echoes" composed by Paul Goldstaub in memory of Mark, as well as the score and program notes. Also materials relating to Sylvia's book Unconditional Love: Mom! Dad! Love Me Please!
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Mark Goldstaub was born April 24, 1951 and died from an AIDS-related illness December 14, 1988. He worked as a publicist in New York City for entertainers including Shirley MacLaine. He is survived by his parents, his brother Paul Goldstaub, and his partner, Edmund Wojcik.
Motivated to share her family's story and to persuade other parents to continue to love their gay children, Sylvia Goldstaub wrote a book in Mark's honor, Unconditional Love: Mom! Dad! Love Me Please! Sylvia has toured the country speaking about her book and her experiences at book stores, religious groups, and AIDS fund-raising events. Sylvia and Bernie have been active members of Parents and Friends of Lesbians and Gays in Florida. Paul Goldstaub, a professor of music, composed "Venetian Echoes" as a tribute to Mark.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Documents include Mark Goldstaub's birth certificate, his tallis and yarmulke, family photographs and correspondence; posters and other material relating to Mark Goldstaub's work and experience with AIDS; videotapes of interviews with Sylvia Goldstaub; a videotape of a public lecture by Sylvia Goldstaub concerning the response of families of PWAs; audiotapes of interviews with Sylvia and Bernie Goldstaub; tape of "Venetian Echoes" composed by Paul Goldstaub, the score, and program notes; correspondence and condolences; folder of material on PFLAG (Parents and Friends of Lesbians and Gays); press releases and biographical information for the family; ephemera collected by Sylvia Goldstaub relating to AIDS activism; a crew jacket for Shirley MacLaine's 1984 Broadway show, for which Mark was publicist; file on AIDS Watch '93, a lobbying effort; and letters of support from people and organizations in response to Sylvia's book Unconditional Love: Mom! Dad! Love Me Please! Includes additional personal material of Mark Goldstaub: birth and death certificates, childhood scrapbooks and autobiographical essay, 1981-1983 photo album; program for memorial service and correspondence of the family of Mark's partner, Edmund Wojcik.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Goldstaub, Mark.; Goldstaub, Sylvia.; Goldstaub, Bernie.; Goldstaub, Paul.; MacLaine, Shirley.; Wojcik, Edmund.; Goldstaub, Paul--Venetian echoes.; Goldstaub, Sylvia--Unconditional love.; Parents & Friends of Lesbians and Gays.
Subjects:
AIDS (Disease).; AIDS (Disease)--Patients.; AIDS (Disease)--Prevention.; AIDS (Disease) in mass media.; Family--New York (State); Gay men--Family relationships.; Parent and child.
Form and Genre Terms:
Audiotapes.; Videotapes.; Ephemera.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Papers
Boxes 1-5, Mapcase
Series II. Audio Materials
Box 7
Series III. Video Materials
Box 6, 7
CONTAINER LIST
- Papers
  - T-shirt, "Walk for Life" to benefit AIDS care and services (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - T-shirt, "South Florida Musicians Unite for AIDS relief" (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 2 T-shirts, "Walk for Life, benefit for AIDS services, Palm Beach County" (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - AIDS buttons, red ribbon ephemera (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
  - PFLAG (Parents and Friends of Lesbians and Gays) printed material including contact sheets, mission statement, information sheets (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - PFLAG printed material including an international directory of affiliates, memos, booklets (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Red ribbon ephemera (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Printed material regarding Sylvia Goldstaub's book; Mark Goldstaub's birth certificate; obituaries; press releases for Mark Goldstaub Public Relations (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Legacy Foundation printed material (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - PFLAG correspondence, booklets, newsletter (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Buttons commemorating Mark Goldstaub (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Venetian Echoes musical score (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Venetian Echoes program notes (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Mark Goldstaub's certificates of achievement; color photocopy of Names Project panel (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Book: If You're Afraid of the Dark, Remember the Night Rainbow, by Cooper Edens (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous AIDS material including NAMES Project Quilt (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - PFLAG newsletter and miscellaneous printed material, Jewish Journal (Palm Beach County South) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Mark Goldstaub's obituary in the New York Times (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - USA Today covering April 1993 Gay Pride March on Washington, D.C. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Printed material regarding Sylvia Goldstaub including press releases, clippings, photocopies of photographs (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Printed material regarding Sylvia Goldstaub including book reviews, correspondence, advertisements (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Family photographs (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Clippings from the New York Times covering April 25, 1993 Gay Pride March in Washington, D.C., miscellaneous printed material about the march (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Aware: HIV Talk Radio clippings (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Clippings from the Ithaca Journal regarding Local Law C (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence in remembrance of Mark Goldstaub (Box 1, Folder 28-30)
  - Miscellaneous AIDS awareness printed material (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
  - HIV/AIDS education booklets (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous clippings concerning AIDS awareness and gay rights (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - AIDS Prevention Guide (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Miscellaneous printed material including theatre programs and poetry (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence from Mark Goldstaub to Edmund Wojcik; photocopies of photographs of Mark Goldstaub and Edmund Wojcik; photocopy of a broadside (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Photo album given to Edmund Wojcik from Mark Goldstaub (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Copy of Unconditional Love: Mom! Dad! Love Me Please! (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Cool Hand Communications, Inc. Spring Catalog 1994 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - AIDSWatch '93 Material (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Various AIDS news publications and pamphlets (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Correspondences and color photos regarding Unconditional Love (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Women's American ORT Certificate (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Press releases regarding Unconditional Love (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Photographs, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Materials for AIDS fundraising events and other events (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence regarding Unconditional Love (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Publicity for Unconditional Love (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Publicity (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Goldstaub clippings (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Mother's Voices" AIDS T-shirt (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "United Together!" T-shirt (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - AIDS and PFLAG pins, wristbands, etc. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 2 AIDS T-shirts (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - AIDS baseball hat (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Photographs (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Publicity for Sylvia Goldstaub Events and Activities, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Brochures and Clippings re: AIDS organizations and safe sex information (Box 2, Folder 12-14)
  - Correspondence, ephemera re: showing of Names Quilt, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Indianapolis newspaper clippings (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Bob LaFont newspaper clipping (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Edmund Wojcik information (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Mark Goldstaub childhood photos (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Mark Goldstaub obituaries, death notices (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Mark Goldstaub 1964 autobiographical essay (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Business (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - HIV/AIDS and the Jewish Community publication (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Sylvia Goldstaub's work: Indianapolis news clippings (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - "Make a Difference Day" T-shirt (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Senior Citizen Center safe sex items (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Various publications (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Sarasota Herald-Tribune clippings on AIDS (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Womens Issues and AIDS in the Nineties! publication (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Correspondences and news clippings re: Unconditional Love (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - HIV/AIDS news clippings (Box 2, Folder 31-32)
  - Various GLBTQ publications (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - AIDS ride information (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Information from CAN (Community AIDS News) (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Sylvia Goldstaub correspondence, Unconditional Love (Box 2, Folder 36-37)
  - AIDS related newspaper clippings (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - AIDS related publications (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - PFLAG/AIDS information (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - AIDS related publications (copies) (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - AIDS related publications (originals) (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Commencement program, Emerson College, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Image of Mark's Names Quilt Panel (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Sylvia's publicity (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Press release Sylvia distributed widely (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - God's Love We Deliver correspondence, 1989-2007 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Ephemera-Southern Tier AIDS Program and other AIDS events (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Sylvia's correspondence, 1998-2008 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Sylvia, public relations, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - West Coast Woman story on Sylvia, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Sylvia's Web page, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Sylvia and Bernie's AIDS activities, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - AIDS brochures, circa 1999 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - AIDS and lesbian/gay clippings, 1997-1999 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Ithaca College theatre program books and clippings (1970-1972); Photographs, clippings, and correspondence (1963-1972) detailing Mark's involvement in theatre, television, and radio at Emerson College in addition to miscellaneous notes and announcements; Clinton Summer Theatre program books, clippings, performance reviews, press books, photograph of Mark Goldstaub while working at the Theatre (Box 3)
  - 2 mugs: "AIDS is a Women's Issue", Palm Beach County Public Heath Unit, white ceramic with two red ribbon decals (Box 3)
  - "Shirley MacLaine on Broadway" tour jacket with "Mark" embroidered on front left panel (Box 4)
  - Southern Tier AIDS Program sweatshirt (Box 4)
  - Sylvia's red ribbon-studded outfit she wore on her publicity tour for the book (Box 4)
  - Prayer shawl and black yarmulke (Box 5)
  - Poster announcing Sylvia Goldstaub at the Bookstar on May 25, 1994; broadsides publicizing Sylvia Goldstaub and her book (Folder 1)
- Audio Materials
  - I Am Prospero and other instrumental works by Paul Goldstaub, includes Venetian Echoes, CD-8 (Box 7)
  - Sylvia Goldstaub on WTKO with Casey Stevens, 7/27/94; 8/3/94, 1994; tr-6731a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Sylvia Goldstaub interview with Liz Sterling, WWNN, Janaury 11, 1994; tr-6732a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Interview with Sylvia Goldstaub, author of Unconditional Love: Mom! Dad! Love Me Please!, and Bernie Goldstaub re: death of son Mark Goldstaub (d. December 14, 1988), WHCU, Ithaca, New York, July 23, 1992 and August 5, 1992, by Casey Stevens, tr-6787a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Venetian Echoes, composed by Dr. Paul Goldstaub "in memory of my dearly beloved brother Mark" (d. December 14, 1988 of AIDS), tr-6788a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - AWARE: HIV TALK RADIO, Unconditional Love: Mom! Dad! Love Me Please!, June 20, 1993, 7 am, 26:10, tr-6789a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - The Legacy Album: South Florida Musicians Unite for AIDS Relief, The Legacy Foundation, Sylvia Goldstaub - ode to her son Mark Goldstaub (d. December 14, 1988), appears on cover, tr-6790a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Keep on Dancing, tr-7194a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - AIDS Support Group Hour with Lee Fowler, November 1, 1989; tr-9970; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - ASC Church, Paul Clement, July 26, 1992; tr-9971; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Aware: HIV Talk Radio with author Sylvia Goldstaub, Chicago, June 20, 1993; tr-9972; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Aware: HIV Talk Radio with author Sylvia Goldstaub, Chicago, June 20, 1993; tr-9973; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Bob Caine, WINO-1230, May 9, 1990; tr-9974; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Casey Stevens, July 2, 1993; tr-9975; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Casey Stevens, Ithaca, NY "Your Health Choices" with Dr. Robert Atkins, July 23, 1992 July 4, 1992; tr-9976; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Casey Stevens, WHCU Ithaca, August 5, 1992; tr-9977; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - "A Common Feeling" (selections), tr-9978; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - "Cool Hand", Sylvia Goldstaub, Delray Beach, Florida WTKO, Ithaca WHCU, Casey Stevens, ---- July 27, 1994 August 3, 1994; tr-9979; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Dr. Martin Kleiman, AIDS, June 7, 1990; tr-9980; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Eastern Kentucky, April 28, 1993; tr-9981; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Fred Fejes, December 3, 1990; tr-9982; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Gay Men's Chorus with Sylvia Goldstaub, P-FLAG Convention, Anaheim, California, October 1990; tr-9983; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Gregg Linde, lecture series, tr-9984; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Ken (Book), August 23, 1990; tr-9985; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Lee Fowler Show, Sylvia and Bernie Goldstaub on AIDS, tr-9986; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Legacy Album, South Florida Musicians Unite for AIDS Relief, tr-9987; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Michael Jackson, Sylvia Goldstaub AIDS, August 14, 1990; tr-9988; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Mike Miller, Sylvia, AIDS, June 4, 1990; tr-9989; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Mom and Dad Dr. Wiewara at AIDS meeting, tr-9990; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - PASTORA Seminar, June 1, 1990; tr-9991; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Sylvia Goldstaub, WHCU Ithaca, NY, July 23, 1992; tr-9992; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Terry Garrity, February 20, 1990; tr-9993; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - "Winds of Change", Mel, tr-9994; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - AWARE: HIV TALK RADIO, Unconditional Love: Mom! Dad! Love Me Please!, May 26, 1993; tr-10082; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
    Sylvia Goldstaub interviewed by telephone from Chicago to Delray Beach, Florida
  - Chris/Sloan-AIDS, December 9, 1989; tr-10083; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Sylvia Goldstaub - LA Radio; Cam Currier KIEV, Michael Jackson, KABC Radio, August 6, 1990; August 14, 1990; tr-10084; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Eastern Kentucky University, Marie Mitchell, April 28, 1993; tr-10085; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Sylvia Goldstaub, Mike Miller - AIDS, June 4, 1990; tr-10086; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Lorena Tong, Hosa Sanders - AIDS TV, KCBS, September 15, 1990; tr-10087; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Chris - AIDS, December 9, 1989; tr-10088; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Sylvia Goldstaub, Gay Men's Chorus P-FLAG Convention, October 1990; tr-10089; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Unconditional Love: Mom! Dad! Love Me Please!. Two interviews with Casey Stevens, WHCU-870 AM, Ithaca, NY., July 23, 1992; August 5, 1992; tr-10090; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Sylvia Goldstaub interview with Liz Sterling, WWNN-Inside Issues, Boca Raton, FL, January 11, 1994; tr-10091; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - WTKO, Ithaca; Casey Stevens, WHCU, July 27, 1994; August 3, 1994; tr-10092; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
- Video Materials
  - VHS Videotapes
    - Publicity for Sylvia Goldstaub's lecture at Temple Beth El Zedeck on WISH-TV 8 News, Indianapolis, Indiana, October 14, 1991. Includes a short clip of Mark Goldstaub's panel in the NAMES Project quilt. Lecture is with Dr. Martin Kleiman, Sylvia Goldstaub's cousin and doctor to Ryan White, V-159 (Box 7)
    - USE COPY of: Publicity for Sylvia Goldstaub's lecture at Temple Beth El Zedeck on WISH-TV 8 News, Indianapolis, Indiana, October 14, 1991. Includes a short clip of Mark Goldstaub's panel in the NAMES Project quilt. Lecture is with Dr. Martin Kleiman, Sylvia Goldstaub's cousin and doctor to Ryan White, V-159B (Box 7)
    - Duplicate of 159, V-160 (Box 7)
    - Broadcast about PFLAG (Parents and Friends of Lesbians and Gays) hosted by Sheldon Katz with Sylvia and Bernie Goldstaub. The Goldstaub's discuss their involvement in the organization and the death of their son Mark from AIDS., V-161 (Box 7)
    - Sylvia Goldstaub discusses her experience as a mother of a gay son who died of AIDS. Vail, Colorado, March 13, 1993, V-162 (Box 7)
    - USE COPY of: Sylvia Goldstaub discusses her experience as a mother of a gay son who died of AIDS. Vail, Colorado, March 13, 1993, V-162B (Box 7)
    - "Paths to Spirituality: AIDS, Homosexuality and Unconditional Love - An Interview with Sylvia and Bernie Goldstaub," Sylvia Goldstaub discusses her experience as a mother of a gay son who died of AIDS. [sound is muffled], V-163 (Box 7)
    - Lecture and book signing, Sylvia Goldstaub, Unconditional Love: Mom! Dad! Love Me Please! at Upstart Crow Bookstore, Long Beach, California 12/2/93, 1993; V-168 (Box 7)
    - Alan Gerstel interview of Sylvia Goldstaub, "Cool Hands" Channel 12, WPEC, Florida, March 3, 1993; V-6972 (Box 7)
    - AIDS Presentation by Sylvia Goldstaub and martin Kleiman, October 14, 1991; V-6973 (Box 7)
    - Born on the 5th of July, on Paths to Spirituality, 1993; V-6974 (Box 7)
    - A Common Feeling, 1994; V-6975 (Box 7)
    - Family Photo, P-FLAG PSA, January 31, 1992; V-6976 (Box 7)
    - Humanistic Side of AIDS: Bonding of Family by Sylvia Goldstaub, V-6977 (Box 7)
    - Larry Kramer, PBS Channel 8, Ithaca, NY, June 23, 1993; V-6978 (Box 7)
    - Long Beach Cable TV Interview with Sylvia and Bernie Goldstaub, V-6979 (Box 7)
    - Mother, Mother: There are No Second Chances, 1989; V-6980 (Box 7)
      Producer: Judy Miller
      Director: Micki Dickoff
      Performers: Bess Armstrong, Polly Bergen, Piper Laurie, John Dye
    - Our Sons, V-6981 (Box 7)
    - Point of View TV, Arthur Dong, V-6982 (Box 7)
    - Point of View TV, Silverlake Life: The View from Here, V-6983 (Box 7)
    - To the Point interview with Bernie and Sylvia Weintraub, Long Beach, California Cable TV, July 27, 1990; V-6984 (Box 7)
    - Tom Kenny interviews Sylvia Goldstaub, Channel 18 Lexington, Kentucky, February 14, 1992; V-6985 (Box 7)
    - Unconditional Love: "Mom! Dad! Love Me! Please!" lecture and book signing, Long Beach, California, December 2, 1993; V-6986 (Box 7)
    - Unconditional Love: "Mom! Dad! Love Me! Please!" lecture and book signing at Upstart Bookstore Long Beach, California, December 2, 1993; V-6987 (Box 7)
    - Unconditional Love: "Mom! Dad! Love Me! Please!" Cable TV Channel 13, Ithaca, NY, August 1992; V-6988 (Box 7)
    - Unconditional Love: "Mom! Dad! Love Me! Please!" Ithaca NY, August 1993; V-6989 (Box 7)
    - Unconditional Love: "Mom! Dad! Love Me! Please!" Sylvia Goldstaub public service announcement for AIDS, August 1992; V-6990 (Box 7)
    - AIDS Benefit in Hollywood, 1994; V-6991 (Box 7)
    - Sylvia Goldstaub lecture, Unconditional Love: Mom! Dad! Love Me Please! - Vail, Colorado, March 13, 1993; V-6996; VHS videotape (Box 7)
    - Sylvia Goldstaub - talk at Barnes and Noble, Sarasota, Florida, June 5, 1998; V-6997; VHS videotape (Box 7)
    - Sylvia and Bernie Goldstaub, Unconditional Love: Mom! Dad! Love Me Please! interviews, 1992-1993; V-6998; VHS videotape (Box 7)
      3 separate clips on one tape. Tom Kenny WXEL 2-14-1992; PSA 8 1992; Alan Gertsel WPEC 3-3-1993.
    - Goldstaub, Unconditional Love: Mom! Dad! Love Me Please! - Cable 13 TV, Ithaca, NY, August 1992; V-6999; VHS videotape (Box 7)
    - Sylvia and Bernie Goldstaub, Humanistic side of AIDS, Unconditional Love - Long Beach Cable TV interview, Sheldon Katz, July 27, 1990; V-7000; VHS videotape (Box 7)
  - 8 mm Film Reels
    - Home movies, 1951-1955; F-960 (Box 6)
      July 1951- Paul's 4th birthday, Mark 3 months old thru 1955 Sylvia and Bernie's 10th Anniversary
    - Home movies, 1955-1957; F-961 (Box 6)
      1955 Spring school play (Paul), Miss Tinnan 2nd grade; 1955 Cabana Club July; 1955 Christmas; 1956 3rd grade (Paul) Mrs. Silva March 14th; April 1956 Mark's 5th birthday; 1956 Cabana Club July; Sept. 1956 Mark's 1st day of Kindergarten; 1957 July Paul's 10th birthday at the Cabana Club; 1957 Sept. school opens, Yom Kippur
    - Home movies, 1957; F-962 (Box 6)
      Sylvia, Bernie and boys Florida trip April 1957- St. Augustine, Marina Studio, Hisleah(?), Acqua Fair(?), Washington DC
    - Home movies, 1958-1960; F-963 (Box 6)
      1958 July Paul leaving for Camp Minisink(?): 1958 July 13 Mark's play at Cabana Club; 1958 July Camp Minisink(?); 1958 Sept. First day school- Paul's first scout hike Oct. 1958; 1959 Mar. Paul's 6th grade play and magic(?); 1959 June Mark's 2nd grade play; 1960 Apr. new home; May 1960 Memorial Day
    - Home movies, 1958; F-964 (Box 6)
      1958 Miss Sloan, Mark 5th grade; Air Force day May 7 1958
    - Homes movies, 1960; F-965 (Box 6)
      Paul's Bar Mitzvah, June 4 1960, Irvington Home Irvington, NJ
    - Home movies, 1960-1962; F-966 (Box 6)
      June 19 1960 Sylvia and Bernie 15th anniversary; Sept.1960 1st day school to Mark's 10th birthday April 24 1961; 1961 July Cape Cod; 1961 Sept. First day school; 1961 Dec. Ice skating; 1962 June 1, Feb. 2
    - Home movies, 1963-1966; F-967 (Box 6)
      1963 First day school and football game; 1964 Decoration for May parade; 1964 Summer and Niagara Falls; 1964 Sept. Paul senior Mark 8th grade and Jr. High; 1965 June Paul graduation from Columbia HS; 1965 Sept. Paul freshman Ithaca College; 1965 Mark freshman Jr. High(?); 1966 Spring Ithaca College; 1966 Mark sophomore Columbia HS; 1966 Paul sophomore Ithaca College
    - Home movies, 1964; F-968 (Box 6)
      1964 Apr. 18 Mark's Bar Mitzvah
    - Home movies, 1967-1970; F-969 (Box 6)
      1967 March Paul (Jr.) Columbia HS; 1967 Paul (Jr.) Ithaca College; 1968 Sept. Paul (Sr.) Horse Head practice; 1968 Sylvia/Mark Senior Columbia HS; 1969 May Paul graduates Ithaca College; 1969 June Mark graduates Columbia HS and prom; 1969 Sept. Mark freshman Ithaca College; 1970 Aug. Mark and Laura sophomores at Ithaca College
    - Home movies, 1971; F-970 (Box 6)
      1971 Jan 17th, "Mom-Dad Israel"
    - Home movies, 1973; F-971 (Box 6)
      1973 Mark's Graduation from Emerson College